<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chris&#39; Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chris&#39; Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 07:52:41 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Dynamic Memory in C&#43;&#43;: The IntegerSet Class</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/seventh-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 07:52:41 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/seventh-post/</guid>
      <description>Mastering Dynamic Memory in C++: The IntegerSet Class Project Overview In a recent academic assignment, I tackled the implementation of a dynamic IntegerSet class in C++. This project was designed to strengthen my skills in handling dynamic memory, working with classes and arrays, and ensuring efficient memory management to avoid leaks.
Objective The primary goal was to implement various methods for the IntegerSet class that allow manipulation and analysis of sets of integers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Shape Inheritance in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/sixth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 07:35:16 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/sixth-post/</guid>
      <description>Implementing Shape Inheritance in C++ In my latest academic endeavor, I explored the concept of inheritance in C++ by creating a hierarchy of shape classes. This project involved constructing a base Shape class and several derived classes like Ellipse, Circle, Rectangle, and Square, each with unique characteristics.
Project Overview The primary goal was to demonstrate inheritance and polymorphism in object-oriented programming. Each class in the hierarchy inherited properties and methods from its parent class while introducing its own unique features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Dynamic Menu Class in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/fifth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 19:49:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/fifth-post/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Dynamic Menu Class in C++ In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my experience developing a dynamic menu system in C++, a project that highlights my skills in creating reusable libraries. This system allows programmers to easily generate custom menus for their applications, with flexibility in menu options and input types.
Project Overview The core of this project lies in the Menu and MenuElement classes. These classes collaborate to create a menu system that can be easily integrated into various applications, offering customizable options and handling user interactions efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Array Library</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/fourth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 19:49:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/fourth-post/</guid>
      <description>#Exploring Array Manipulations in C++ In this post, I delve into an intricate C++ project focused on array manipulations, which forms a part of my advanced programming studies. This project accentuates my understanding of basic data structures in C++ and exhibits my skills in implementing various array-based algorithms.
##Project Overview This project, consisting of two primary components - the main function and the array_library, explores different operations on arrays, such as searching, sorting, and statistical analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expression Evaluator</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 13:33:51 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/third-post/</guid>
      <description>Step-by-Step Evaluation of Arithmetic Expressions in C++ In this post, I explore a C++ project that I developed for evaluating arithmetic expressions step-by-step. The project, part of my coursework, highlights my proficiency in utilizing C++ standard library features and understanding complex programming concepts.
Project Insight The project comprises three main components: the &amp;lsquo;main&amp;rsquo; function, the &amp;rsquo;evaluator&amp;rsquo; module, and &amp;rsquo;test scripts&amp;rsquo;. Each plays a vital role in reading, processing, and evaluating arithmetic expressions, outputting each step of the evaluation process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Points</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 15:41:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/second-post/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Geometry with C++: Three Points Analysis In this post, I delve into a C++ project that leverages geometric principles to analyze whether three points form a line or a triangle. Titled &amp;ldquo;Lab 1 - threepoints.cpp,&amp;rdquo; this project exemplifies the application of mathematical concepts in computer programming, demonstrating my grasp of both C++ programming and geometric computation.
In-Depth Look at the Three Points Analysis The program&amp;rsquo;s essence lies in taking three points as input and applying geometric formulas to deduce their collective shape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guessing Game</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:25:35 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>A guessing game to start coding in C++ In this post, I want to delve into a fun and interactive way that I begin coding in C++. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss a simple guessing game that not only introduces basic programming concepts like loops and conditional statements but also gives insight into some fundamental data structures in C++.
Deep Dive into the Guessing Game The game&amp;rsquo;s primary objective is for the player to guess a randomly generated number within a specified range.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
