<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chris&#39; Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chris&#39; Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 13:33:51 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Expression Evaluator</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 13:33:51 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/third-post/</guid>
      <description>Step-by-Step Evaluation of Arithmetic Expressions in C++ In this post, I explore a C++ project that I developed for evaluating arithmetic expressions step-by-step. The project, part of my coursework, highlights my proficiency in utilizing C++ standard library features and understanding complex programming concepts.
Project Insight The project comprises three main components: the &amp;lsquo;main&amp;rsquo; function, the &amp;rsquo;evaluator&amp;rsquo; module, and &amp;rsquo;test scripts&amp;rsquo;. Each plays a vital role in reading, processing, and evaluating arithmetic expressions, outputting each step of the evaluation process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Points</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 15:41:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/second-post/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Geometry with C++: Three Points Analysis In this post, I delve into a C++ project that leverages geometric principles to analyze whether three points form a line or a triangle. Titled &amp;ldquo;Lab 1 - threepoints.cpp,&amp;rdquo; this project exemplifies the application of mathematical concepts in computer programming, demonstrating my grasp of both C++ programming and geometric computation.
In-Depth Look at the Three Points Analysis The program&amp;rsquo;s essence lies in taking three points as input and applying geometric formulas to deduce their collective shape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guessing Game</title>
      <link>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:25:35 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Kendallchris.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>A guessing game to start coding in C++ In this post, I want to delve into a fun and interactive way that I begin coding in C++. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss a simple guessing game that not only introduces basic programming concepts like loops and conditional statements but also gives insight into some fundamental data structures in C++.
Deep Dive into the Guessing Game The game&amp;rsquo;s primary objective is for the player to guess a randomly generated number within a specified range.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
